if you want to rank on Google I will
help you in this video I'll go step by
step on what's working with my websites
with my clients's websites and once you
see the processes you're going to be
like it's not that difficult now four
things off the bat Google search console
analytics sitap and Page index and and
this is all for Bonsai Mary if I were to
show you the mobile view we've kind of
revamped the homepage a little bit you
can see a little bit of dynamic things
going on looks nice but what are we
doing that's so special to get this kind
of growth I'm going to show you look
here we have
478 traffic recently and that's up from
when we recreated this website in April
of last year and if we go to the Google
analytics we can see a little bit
different picture we're receiving 800
800 you know 800 700 700 we are going up
in traffic the total we could be
receiving this month is 30,000 if it
continues on this pace we could hit we
could hit 100,000 visitors in this first
quarter of 2024 so getting into this
diagram the goal of many of my SEO
campaigns is to maintain and gain right
we have to maintain what we've earned
and we have to gain more traffic a lot
of times we just want to gain more gain
more while we forget everything in the
background so there's two processes at
play here reactive SEO right and we have
proactive SEO and both work well the
first one reactive is what most people
are accustomed to right um hcu the
traffic drops what do I do next freaking
out traffic is increasing on a topic
what to do next you're just observing
and reacted and I'll show you a great
way to employ reactive SEO the first
step and remember this is free is to
come up here to date and you want to go
to compare and I want to compare say the
last s days to the previous period
comparing is so powerful and it's free
if you have Google search console hooked
up then you're going to go to pages
right here and then I I just merely want
to know the difference okay I click here
and I can see the difference a positive
number 38 that means this article right
here small Greenhouse which we revamp
uh very recently we re revamped this uh
article is doing really well compared to
last week I mean that's 14 clicks last
week and 52 now big difference but the
inverse is true of this one so we have a
clicks difference of 21 so if we were to
go to this article and this is important
this has a lot of clicks on the website
I know that because I know the website
and it has 121 clicks so the disparity
of 121 versus 142 both are still big
numbers for this website I'm not worried
about it I'm worried about something
that has you know a decent number and
then it fell off the face of the Earth
so we're going to search and remember we
are in a ranking a positive ranking
State on this website right now this one
right here this one right here so look
it had 17 last week and now seven this
week and we come here and you can see
this type of antherium It kind of stinks
this article stinks in a way because
there's no pictures there's nothing here
now another way to do it is at refs
right and you can see here the chart the
blue is the domain rating and we really
haven't gone after any back links on
this website but I really plan to in
2024 I think it's the insulating factor
and I can rank higher for sure so the
graph looks good but if we come over to
organic keywords this is where it gets
interest in I can see so compare with
the previous week the previous previous
month previous month gives us more I
don't want to say accurate view but
things can fluctuate volatility right
previous month is pretty darn good but
you're going to see a lot of positive
things positive positive so I can come
here and I can say position was either
lost declined let's go there if there
was anything sticking out like ooh that
hurts we'd be like why did that happen
you see the pictures here image packs if
I lose those uh I'm okay with that but
here right here filad dendrin what is it
called Deja Vu this article right here
we did revamp it could I make it better
ATS is saying that you know we took a
little bit of hit so what I can do is I
can copy this URL I can come back to
Google search console I can come here go
to page post it in here I want accurate
accurate accurate things we're not going
to compare we're going to go here we're
going to do uh filter we're going to do
last 28 days what are the true metrics
on this uh page page by Page this
matters and you can see we're kind of
flatlining are We receiving too much
traffic to care about it is there enough
traffic on this keyword to care about it
these are the questions we have to ask
now we're going to edit this article so
we are going to edit it but why why do
we care it doesn't seem like there's a
lot of traffic here and you have to
listen to me on this if you have good
content and you have bad content on your
website the bad content can drag down
everything that's called a sitewide
penalty and I think a lot of people saw
that with hcu nonetheless if we're going
to come down here what are we going to
do to edit it I'm going to go first to
the featured image I'm going to push
this in here I just want one that looks
contrasted a contrast right that one
white and green looks good to me boom
and then this first portion here welcome
to comprehensive care guide let's get
rid of that that stinks right I want a
better look this right here would be a
better intro it tells you about the
plant right off the bat right so that's
exactly what I'm going to do boom get
rid of that and let's bold something
that in itself right there I'd be happy
with you know that's very kind of lazy
way to go about it but make the article
better make it different update right
now you're going to push update you're
going to click View Post and then when I
have this right here I'm going to grab
it contrl C and I'm going to come up
here boom right this is us asking Google
okay we changed it a bit please Index
this right testing live URL if it can be
indexed and you're going to see Google's
going to be like yes it can be indexed
good it takes a minute or two but the
point here is revise and then ask Google
to reindex your page and when things go
well this is what it looks like this is
exactly what I look for on websites this
is when velocity of content matters
right this is the sitemap you can go to
all known pages I don't care about this
this doesn't matter go to bonsy mar.com
sitap index these are the the pages on
the website that we created is Google
given us green that means it's indexed
it online it means that people can see
it when they search in keywords right
this is what we want up up and away
that's what you want to see then when
you see that you put your foot to the
pedal and new content in revisionary
content is so important now moving on to
proactive SEO I really think this is
what separates websites we're accustomed
to this whole adage of let's just create
articles and let them cook and forget
about them I don't think that's the way
anymore I think Google is required more
of us so it's all about your processes
we have to create processes for this to
go well now one way that I have done
really well with proactive SEO is coming
to my sitemap very easy very free to do
right just do this I can come and you'll
see there's the URL I can click in any
of these the images and the last
modification date this tells me a lot
about my competitor's websites too I can
just jump on their sit map nonetheless I
can tell you for a fact any of these
articles I click in this one s mode mold
I can talk uh this article stinks and it
doesn't stink for reasons you may think
but it stinks for page engagement why
because it has two images and it was
done back in May anything done back in
May I know I was not doing the same
processes I was just testing chat gbt to
just pump out content and it ranked and
it did well but we can do much better so
I would sort and this is exactly what
I'm doing I say to my team if you see
anything that is done before X date we
need new articles and what I do is a
completely new batch of Articles new
100% new copy and I'll show you what
that looks like furthermore look here
images I have articles on filad dendrin
how cold can filad dendrin tolerate like
this this this article is ranking by the
way this is doing well but it's just
informational text I have something like
a thousand filad dendrin pictures on the
website why not use them why not come in
here and revise these zero image
articles with with images of filad
dendrin now for for an example this was
just posted this one right here Bonsai
pests as I was creating this video like
our team member just posted this I just
saw it come up so this is a perfect
example this one was one of the older
ones that was redone they have new
pictures the format is awesome realize
this website I hardly touch at all it's
all just team members creating it I just
give keywords and some slight directions
and it just goes goes goes so how did
they do this and one of the coolest
Parts is the images right the most pests
in bonsai a cool image right 16 by9
we'll get into that aphids a kind of
demonstration of aphids look at this
let's keep going spider mites very cool
mbug so what we do how you do this is
grab the text after you've created the
text then you come to chat PT give me
four 16x9 cartoon images why 16x9 it's
because Google discover likes that
format uh rela to this text make sure
the H2S are represented and then boom we
just give it the whole stinking thing
right and it will do exactly what we
asked of it it's going to say okay let's
do scale insects let's do aphids spiderm
SMY bugs and here are images it just
came up with similar to what we just saw
now what else can you do you can use
tools like xn convert you can push them
to webp definitely rename the file name
and uh what else alt text we do alt text
for all images as well now this is the
inside brains of bonsai Mary I want to
show you this because this one article
could get 30,000 uh visitors per month
by itself and we're going after bigger
terms now so the best indoor plants for
beginners that's what it's going to be
titled but you have to realize how we're
doing it so what best plants what are
the best plants this is a listic cool
right the 47 best plants and here they
all are we merely asked chat gbt you
know give us some ideas and I don't know
how many we had we had like that's 81
different plants and then what we're
doing here is gathering the genus
species we're going to have a title and
then over here is the URL some of these
are already existing on the website
therefore don't do anything and when we
create these type of Articles this is
what it looks like the 47 different
types of bonsai trees and I mean the the
the format's pretty simple in other
videos I showed you the hammer format we
usually do two or three paragraphs
bullet points looks nice readers can
read it very easily and people just want
to see pictures and they want to read a
little thing a little SEO stuff but
realize all of these things I can click
here and it links down to the article
they can learn more and that's going to
help with page engagement we want people
to crawl down into our websites that
matters more than anything nowadays I
think and I think it always has mattered
uh here's another example flower and
Bonsai so 22 most beautiful flower and
Bonsai you know same format there's
nothing new here just rinse and repeat
because although this is a nice chart
and it's nice that we survived hcu for
now it's going up that really you know
400 call 500 clicks a day that still
doesn't matter that's not going to give
us the income that's excitable in any
measure right and how we're going to get
there is through listicle type of posts
that draw in huge amounts of traffic